In the previous segment we saw how to
build public key encryption from trapdoor
在上一节里我们了解了如何从陷门函数中构建公钥加密，
functions, in this segment we're going to
build a classic trapdoor function called
在这一节我们将构造一个经典的陷门函数—RSA.
首先让我们先来回顾一下什么是陷门函数。
RSA. But first let's quickly review what a
trapdoor function is. So recall that a
回想下陷门函数由三种算法组成。分别是密钥生成模式算法，
trapdoor function is made up of three
algorithms. There is a key generation
函数本身和函数的逆。
algorithm, the function itself, and the
inverse of the function. The key
密钥生成模式算法输出一个公钥和一个私钥。在这种情况下，
generation algorithm outputs a public key
and a secret key. And in this case, in
这公钥将定义一个函数，这个函数会将一集合X映射到本身。
this lecture the public key is going to
define a function that maps the set X onto
之所以我把这些叫做陷门排列，与陷门函数相对照，
itself. Which is why I call these things
trapdoor permutations, as opposed to
仅仅是因为这个函数将X映射到本身，
trapdoor functions, simply because the
function maps X onto itself, whereas a
然而陷门函数可能会将一集合X映射到一任意集合Y。
trapdoor function might map the set X to
some arbitrary set Y. Now given the public
key, the function, as we say, basically
defines this function from the set X to
现在给这个函数赋予一公钥，正如我们所说的，定义这函数是从集合X到集合X的。
the set X. And then given the secret key,
we can invert this function. So this
然后给一个私钥，我们能反转这个函数。
function F evaluates the function in the
forward direction, and this function F
所以函数F从正面评估本身，反转，也就是
inverse, which means the secret key SK,
computes F in the reverse direction. Now
通过私钥SK从反面计算函数F。
we say that the trapdoor permutation is
secure if the function defined by the
如果被公钥定义的函数事实上是单向函数则陷门置换是安全的，
public key is in fact a one-way function,
which means that it's easy to evaluate,
也就是说评估容易但没有陷门，
but without the trapdoor, the secret
trapdoor, it's difficult to invert. Before
秘密的陷门是很难反转的。
we look at our first example of a trapdoor
permutation, I want to do a quick review
在看第一个例子之前，我想对将用到的必需的一些算法
of some necessary arithmetic facts that
we're gonna need. And in particular,
做一个快速回顾。特别地，
let's look at some arithmetic facts
modulo composites. So here we have our
让我们来看一些以复合体为模的算法实例，所以有模数N,
modulus N, which happens to be a product
of two primes, and you should be thinking
它恰好是两个素数产生的，取两大致等价的数P，Q，
of P and Q as roughly equal size numbers,
since particular P and Q are both roughly
使二者恰好大致上是N的平方根
on the size of square root of N. So both
are roughly the same size. Recall that we
二者大致相同。
denoted by ZN the set of integers from
zero to N minus one, and we said that we
回想一下,我们用ZN来表示从0到N - 1的一组整数,
can do addition and multiplication module N. We denoted by ZN star the set of
我们可以用模N来做加法和乘法。我们用ZN*来标记其中的可逆元素。
invertible elements in ZN. So these are
all the elements, which have a modular
所以所有的元素都有模块化的倒数。
inverse. And we said that actually X is
invertible if and only if it's relatively
我们说X是可逆的当且仅当它与N互质。
prime to N. Moreover, I also told you that
the number of invertible elements in ZN
另外，我也会告诉你可逆元素的数量用这个函数φ(N)来表示。
star is denoted by this function phi(N). So phi(N)
is the number of invertible elements in ZN
所以φ(N)就是ZN中可逆元素的数目，
star, And I told you that when N is a
product of two distinct primes, then in
当N是由两个不同的素数产生时，
fact phi(N) is equal to (P - 1) times (Q - 1) and if you extend that out, you
事实上φ(N)等于(P - 1)乘以(Q - 1)，如果你延长，
see that this is really equal to (N - P - Q + 1). Now remember that I said
这确实是等于(N - P - Q + 1)。现在记住我说的
that P and Q are on the order of square
root of N which means that P + Q is
P和Q是N的平方根，P+Q也是N的平方根。
also on the order of square root of N.
Which means that really phi(N) is on the
那么φ(N)大约是（N - 2） N的平方根
order of N minus two square root of N. So,
in other words, it's very, very close to
换句话说，它会非常非常接近于N
N. Basically, subtracting the square root
of N from a number, this is from, N is
基本上，从一个数减去N的平方根，
going to be a huge number in our case,
like 600 digits. And so subtracting from a
N将是一个巨大的数字在我们的例子中,像600位数。
600 digit number, the square root of that
600 digit number, namely a 300 digit
从一个600位数中减去,这个600位数字的平方根,也就是一个300位数字，
number, hardly affects the size of the
number. Which means that phi(N) is really,
几乎不影响这个数字的大小。也就是φ(N)是真的
really, really close to N, and I want you
to remember that, because we will actually
真的真的很接近N，我想让你记住，因为我们时不时的会用到这个，
be using this now and again. And so the
fact that phi(N) is really close to N, means
所以这个事实，意味着
that if we choose a random element modulo
N It's very, very, very likely to be in ZN
如果我们选一个随机元素模N，它会非常非常非常有可能是ZN*。
star. So it's very unlikely that by
choosing a random element in ZN, we will
所以这是非常不可能的通过选一个随机元素，我们最终将
end up choosing an element that is not
invertable. Okay. So just remember that,
选出不可逆的一元素。所以就记住，
that in fact almost all elements in ZN are
actually invertible. And the last thing
事实上几乎所有的ZN中的元素都是可逆的。
that we'll need is Euler's theorem, which
we covered last week, which basically says
最后我们需要学习的就是欧拉定理，我们上周学过的，
that for any element X in ZN star, if I
raise X to the power of phi(N), I get one, in
对于ZN*中任一元素，如果我把X加到φ(N)上，我会得到ZN中一个数。
ZN. So in other words, I get 1 modulo N. I'll say it one more time because this
换句话说，，我得到1模N。我再说一次
is gonna be critical to what's coming.
Again X to the phi(N) is equal to 1 modulo
因为这对下面要说的是至关重要的。X加到φ(N)上等价于1模N。
N. So now that we have the necessary
background we can actually describe the
现在我们要有必需的背景来描述RSA陷门置换。
RSA trapdoor permutation. This is a classic,
classic, classic construction in
这是一个很经典很经典的概念在密码学中，
cryptography that was first published in
Scientific American back in 1977, this is
它是在1977年首次被刊登在科学美国人封面上的，
a very well known article in cryptography.
And ever since then, this was 35 years
这个一篇周所周知的文章在密码学界。从那时到现在，它有35年了，
ago, the RSA trapdoor permutation has been used
extensively in cryptographic applications.
RSA陷门置换被广泛地应用在用密码写的应用程序中。
For example, SSL and TLS use RSA both for
certificates and for key exchange. There
例如，SSL和TLS用RSA来进行认证和密钥交换。
are many secure email systems and secure
file systems that use RSA to encrypt
有许多安全的电子邮件系统和安全的文件系统用RSA来加密邮件和文件
emails and encrypt files in the file
system. And there are many, many, many
在文件系统中。还有许多许多其他这个系统的应用程序。
other applications of this system. So this
is a very, very classic, crypto
所以它是一个非常非常经典的加密结构，
construction, and I'll show you how it
works. I should say that RSA is named for
我会向你展示它是如何工作的。
its inventors, Ron Rivest, Adi Shamir and
Len Adleman, who were all at MIT at the
RSA是以它的发明者Ron Rivest, Adi Shamir和Len Adleman命名的
time they made this important discovery.
So now we're ready to describe the RSA
他们都是在MIT完成这项重要的工作的
trapdoor permutation. To do that, I have
to describe the key generation algorithm,
那么我们来描述RSA陷门置换，首先我需要描述密钥产生算法
the function A and the function AE 1.
So let's see. So the way the key
函数A和函数AE
generation algorithm works is as follows:
What we do is we generate two primes, P
密钥产生算法是这样做的：
and Q, each would be, say on the order of
1000 bits, so, you know, roughly 300
我们生成2个素数P、Q，每个大约1000比特，300十进制位
digits, and then the RSA modulus is simply
going to be the product of those two
RSA模就等于两个素数的乘积
primes. The next thing we do is we pick
two exponents, e and d, such that e times
然后我们选择两个指数e和d，使得e乘d等于1模φ(N)
d is 1 modulo phi(N). What this means is
that e and d first of all are relatively
这意味着e和d首先与φ(N)互素
prime to phi(N) and second of all they're
actually modular inverses of one another,
其次它们互为模φ(N)的逆
modulo phi(N). And then we output the public
key as the pair N,e and the
然后我们输出公钥对(N,e)
secret key is the secret key N,d. I should mention that the exponent e,
私钥为(N,d)
that the number e is sometimes called the
encryption exponent and the exponent d is
这个指数e有时称为加密指数
sometimes called the decryption exponent.
And you'll see why I keep referring to
指数d有时称为解密指数
these as exponents in just a second. Now
the way the RSA function itself is
马上你就会知道为什么我称它为指数
defined is really simple. For simplicity
I'm gonna define it as the function
RSA函数定义是很简单的。简单起见，我称之为从ZN*到ZN*的函数
from ZN star to ZN star. And the way
the function is defined is simply given an
这个函数定义为给定输入X
我们取X在ZN中的e次幂
input X, all we do is we simply take X and
raise it to the power of e in ZN. So we
因此我们只需计算X^e mod N
just compute X to the e, modulo N. That's
it. And then to decrypt, what we do is we
解密时，给定输入Y，我们只需计算Y的d次幂模N
simply, given an input Y, we simply raise
Y to the power of d, modulo N. And that's
现在你知道我把e,d称为指数的原因了
it. So now you can see why as I refer to e
and d as exponents. They're the things
它们是X和Y的指数。因此我们来快速验证F^-1确实是F的逆
that X and Y are being raised to. So let's
quickly verify that F inverse really does
我们来看计算Y^d时会发生什么
invert the function F. So let's see what
happens when we compute Y to the d. So
假设Y正好是函数RSA在X的值
suppose Y itself happens to be the RSA
function of some value X. In which case,
这时Y^d等于RSA(X)^d
what Y to the d is, is really RSA of X to
the power of d. While X by itself is
即等于X^e mod N。因此Y^d等于X^ed mod N
simply gonna be X to the e modulo N, And
therefore, Y to the d is simply X to the e
这里又使用了指数相乘规则
times d modulo N. Again, just using rules
of exponentiation, the exponents multiply,
所以我们得到X^(ed)。但ed等于什么呢？
so we get X to the e times d. But what do
we know about e times d? e times d we said
ed等于1 mod φ(N)。这说明存在某个整数k
is one modulo phi(N). And what that means is
there exists some integer such that e
使得ed=kφ(N)+1，也就是说ed=1 mod φ(N)
times d is equal to K times phi(N) plus one.
This is what it means that e times d is
因此我们把ed换成kφ(N)+1
one modulo phi(N). So, we can simply replace e
times d by K times phi(N)+1. So, that's
我写在这里。我们有X^(kφ(N)+1)
what I wrote here. So, we have X to the
power of K times phi(N)+1. But now again
现在再用指数法则，我们能把式子重写为（X^φ(N))^k*x
just using rules of exponentiation, we can
re-write this as X to the power of phi(N) to
这与kφ(N)+1作为指数相同
the power of K times X. This is really the
same thing as K times phi(N)+1 as the
我只是把指数放在不同项上
exponent. I just kind of separated the
exponent into it's different components.
现在通过欧拉定理，我们知道X^φ(N)等于1
Now, X to the phi(N) by Euler's theorem, we know
that X to the phi(N) is equal to one. So what
所以整个乘积等于多少？因为X^φ(N)=1
is this whole product equal to? Well since
X to the phi(N) is equal to one, one to
1^k=1，因此整个式子就等于1
the K is also equal to one, so this whole
thing over here is simply equal to one.
只剩下X，因此我们证明了
And what we're left with is X. So what we
just proved is that if I take the output of
如果计算RSA函数的输出的d次幂，就得到X
the RSA function and raise it to the power
of 'd', I get back X. Which means that
这说明d次幂就是RSA函数的逆
raising to the power of 'd' basically
inverts the RSA function, which is what we
就是这样。这就是函数的完整描述
wanted to show. So that's it, that's the
whole description of the function, we've
我们描述了密钥的产生，函数自身，即计算e次幂模N
described the key generation. The function
itself, which is simply raising things to
函数的逆，即计算d次幂模N
the power of e modulo N, and the inversion
function which is simply raising things to
接下来的问题是，为什么这个函数是安全的
the power of d, also modulo N. The next
question is, why is this function secure?
换句话说，为什么函数是单向的，如果我只有公钥但没有私钥？
In other words, why is this function one
way if all I have is just a public key,
为了说明函数是单向的
but I don't have the secret key? And so to
argue that this function is one way we
我们表述RSA假设，它告诉我们RSA是一个单向置换
basically state the RSA assumption which
basically says that the RSA function is a
正式的表达是这样
one way permutation. And formally the way
we state that is that, basically for all
对于所有的有效算法A，如果产生两个随机素数p和q
efficient algorithms, A, it so happens
that if I generate two primes p and q,
把它们相乘再模N，然后随机在ZN*中取y
random primes p and q. I multiply them to
get to modulus N and then I choose a
然后把模数，指数和y给算法A
random 'y' in ZN star. And now I give
the modulus, the exponent and this 'y' to
我得到RSA在y的逆的概率
algorithm A, the probability that I'll get
the inverse of RSA at the point Y, mainly
也就是得到y^(1/e)的概率
I'll get Y to the power of one over E.
That's really what the inverse is. This
这个事件的概率可以忽略不计。因此这种假设叫做RSA假设。
probability is negligible. So this
assumption is called the RSA assumption.
它指出RSA是一种提供公共密钥的单向置换。
It basically states that RSA is a one way
permutation just given the public [key?]. And
并且这是一种暗门置换因为其中包含暗门。
therefore, it is a trapdoor permutation
because it has a trapdoor. And makes this
并且这使得每个知道暗门的人都很容易作反置。所以我们现在有了一个安全
easy to invert for anyone who knows the
trap door. So now that we have a secure
的暗门置换。我们可以简单地把它插入到我们为公共密钥加密的函数中，
trap door permutation, we can simply plug
that into our construction for public key
这就得到了世界上第一个公共密钥加密系统。
encryption, and get our first real world
public key encryption system. And so what
我们要做到就是简单地将RSA的暗门置换插入
we'll do is we'll simply plug the, the RSA
trapdoor permutation into the iso standard
我们之前已经见过的iso标准函数中。所以，回想一下，
construction that we saw in the previous
segment. So, if you recall, that
这个结构基于一个必须提供认证加密的对称加密系统。
construction was based on a symmetric
encryption system that had to provide
这个结构还基于哈希函数。
authenticated encryption. And it was also
based on a hash function. Then mapped
然后映射进RS是A的世界，它将元素映射进
while transferring it into the world of
RSA, it maps elements in
ZN，映射进对称密钥系统中的私密密钥里。 And now the
ZN, into secret keys for the
symmetric key system. And now the
这时加密体系工作的方式很容易描述。一般来说，算法G
way the encryption scheme works is really
easy to describe. Basically algorithm G
只运行RSA密钥算法并且产生一个公共密钥和一个私密密钥。
just runs the RSA key generation algorithm
and produces a public key and a secret
就像之前一样，所以你会发现公共密钥包含加密指数
key. Just as before. So you notice the
public key contains the encryption
私密密钥包含解密指数。
exponent and the, secret key contains the
decryption exponent. And the way we
并且我们是按顺序加密。接下来，我们要从ZN中随机地选取一个X。
encrypt is as follows. Well, we're going
to choose a random X in ZN. We're going
我们要对这个X申请使用RSA函数。 我们要从这个X中通过哈希函数演绎出一个对称密钥
to apply the RSA function to this X, we're
going to deduce a symmetric key from this
因此我们通过X计算出H并获得密钥K，接着输出Y和
X by hashing it, so we compute H of X to
obtain the key K, and then we output this
在对称密钥K下的信息加密后的结果。
Y along with the encryption of the message
under the symmetric key K. And in
事实上，哈希函数H是运用了SHA-256来进行加密计算的，
practice, the hash function H would be
just implemented just using SHA-256, and
因此你才可以运用SHA-256的输出来生成一个稍后用来
you would use the output of SHA-256 to
generate a symmetric key that could then
作为对称加密的助手的对称密钥。这就是加密的过程。
be used for the symmetric encryption
assistant. So that's how we would encrypt
接下来解密的过程和我们之前学过的很相似，
and then the way we would decrypt is
pretty much as we saw in the previous
第一个步骤，是用私密密钥
segment, where the first thing we would do
is we would use the secret key to invert
倒置密文的报头。所以我们可以计算出RSA在Y下的倒置
the header of the ciphertext. So we would
compute RSA invert of Y, that would give
这样会得到一个值X. 接下来对X使用哈希函数，我们可以得到密钥K。
us the value X. Then we would apply the
hash function to X so that this would give
接下来对密文中的对称系统运行解密算法
us the key K. And then we would run the
decryption algorithm for the symmetric
这样就可以得到原始信息M。
system on the ciphertext and that would
produce the original message m. And then
我们之前还学过一个理论，如果RSA的暗门排列是安全的。
we stated a theorem in the previous
segment to say that if the RSA trapdoor
ES和Ds，那么对称加密系统[inaudible]
permutation is secure, Es and Ds, the
symmetric encryption scheme [inaudible]
会提供经过验证的加密。正如我们所说，H只是一种随机的预报。
provides authenticated encryption. And as
we said, H is just random oracle. It's,
它只是一种从ZN到密钥区的随机函数。
you know, kind of a random function from
ZN to the key space. Then, in fact, this
事实上，这种安全挑选密文的系统是一种很好的可以用作公共密钥的系统。
system is chosen cipher text secure, and
is a good public key system to use.
那么现在我们就得到了第一个优质公共密钥系统运用的例子。
So now that we have our first example of a
good public key system to use, I wanna
这里我要提示大家RSA不能用于加密的情况。
quickly warn you about how not to use RSA
for encryption. And this again something
这又是我们之前讲过的内容。现在我又要重复一遍，
that we said in the previous segment. And
I'm going to repeat it here, except I'm
把之前的理论针对RSA再讲一遍，所以我喜欢把这个称为RSA课本。
going to make it specific to RSA. So
I'd like to call this, textbook RSA.
当你要使用RSA加密时
Which basically is the first thing that
comes to mind when you think about
也就是私密密钥和公共密钥像之前那样规定
encrypting using RSA, namely, the secret
key and the public key will be as before.
此处我们不用哈希函数得到对称密钥的方法，
But now instead of running through, a hash
function to generate a symmetric key, what
而是直接用RSA加密来得到信息M。
we would do is we would directly use RSA
to encrypt the given message M. And then
我们首先想到的是直接用解密指数对密文进行解密
we would directly use the decryption
exponent to decrypt the cipher text and
得到纯文本M. 我要把这种称为RSA课本，因为 because there are many
obtain the plain text M. I'm going to call
this textbook RSA, because there are many
有很多种讲解RSA用这种方式来加密的课本。但是这么说是完全的错误。
textbooks that describe RSA encryption in
this way. And this is completely wrong.
这不是RSA加密的方式。这是一种不安全的系统。特别是，
This is not how RSA encryption works.
It's an insecure system. In particular,
它是对称性加密，所以它可能不能保证语义安全。
it's deterministic encryption, and so it
can't possibly be semantically secure, but
但是事实上有很多攻击存在，比如我接下来给你们展示一分钟内的一个攻击
in fact there are many attacks exist that
I'm going to show you an attack in just a
但是这里我想讲清楚的一点，
minute, but the message that I want to
make clear here, is that RSA, all it is,
是RSA是一个暗门置换。对它自己来说，不是一个加密系统。 You have to
is a trap door permutation. By itself
it's not an encryption system. You have to
我们必须完善一下它，比如加上ISO标准，使他成为一个加密系统。
embellish it with this ISO standard for
example, to make it into an encryption
仅仅就自己来说，这只是个函数。那么如果我们用课本RSA的话
system. By itself, all it is, is just a
function. So let's see what goes wrong if
我们会犯什么错误呢。换句话说，如果你想直接用RSA加密一条消息，
you try to use textbook RSA, In other
words, if you try to encrypt a message
我会给你一个来自互联网上的攻击，
using RSA directly. And I'll give you an
example attack from the world of the web.
假设我们有个网络服务器，它有一个RSA私密密钥。我们用N和D来表示。
So imagine we have a web server. The web
server has an RSA secret key. Here's it's
我们有一个浏览器正在尝试建立一个安全的SSL会话
denoted by N and D. And here we have a web
browser who's trying to establish a secure
通过web服务器。所以SSL的工作方式为
session, a secure SSL session, with the web
server. So the way SSL works is that the
由浏览器发送客户你好这样的消息开始
web browser starts off by sending this
client hello message saying, hey, I want
你好，我想和你建立一个安全会话。web服务器即响应相应服务器的消息
to set up a secure session with you. The
web server responds with a server hello
消息包括了服务器的公钥。之后浏览器将运行
message that contains the server's public
key And then the web browser will go ahead
并且生成一个随机的预主密钥K，它将用K加密
and generate a random what's called a
premaster secret K, it will encrypt the
预主密钥并用密文发送给服务器
premaster secret using K and send the
result in ciphertext over to the web
服务器会进行解密得到K
server. The web server will decrypt and
then the web server will also get K, so
所以两者会得到一个共享密钥，用来进行之间的安全会话
now the two have a shared key that they
can use to then secure a session between
如果我们直接使用RSA函数来加密K会出什么错误?
them. So I want to show you what goes
wrong if we directly use the RSA function
换句话说，如果直接将K加密为k的e次方模N
for encrypting K. In other words, if
directly K is encrypted as K to the e
为了论证，我们假设K为一个64比特的密钥
modulo N. Just for the sake of argument
let's suppose that K is a 64-bit key.
我们将K取一在0到2的64次方范围内的整数
We're going to treat K as an integer in
the range as zero to 2 to the 64.
更准确的说是2的64次方减一，现在我们继续往下
More precisely two to the 64 minus one,
and now what we're going to do is the
首先，假设K取大致相等的一串数
following. First of all, suppose it so
happens that K factors into a product of
我们把K写成K1乘K2，并且K1和K2都为整数
roughly equal sized numbers. So K we can
write as K1 times K2, where K1 and K2 are
并且都小于2的34次方。事实证明这种情况发生
integers. And both are say less than two
to the 34. So, it turns out this happens
的概率约为百分之二十，所以有五分之一的情况下K可以这么写
with probability roughly twenty percent so
one in five times K can actually be
但是现在如果将K，K=K1×K2加入方程式中
written in this way. But, now if we plug
this K, K=K1 x K2 if we plug that into the
定义你看到的密文可以简单地用K1×K2替换K
equation that defines the cipher text you
see that we can simply substitute K by K1 x k2
然后我们就可以把K1换到另一边。这个方程式就结束了
and then we can move k1 to the other side.
So then we end up with this equation here,
即K1的e次方分之C等于K2的e次方。注意，如果我在两边
namely C over K1 to the e is equal to K2 to the e. You notice if I multiply both
同乘K1的e次方，就得到了C等于K1×K2的e次方
sides by K1 to the e, I get that C is
equal to K1 times K2 to the e,
得到的就是这个方程。我只是把K用K1×K2替换
which is precisely this equation here.
Okay, so all I did is I just replaced K by
然后再用K1的e次方分开。现在这看起来很熟悉吧
K1 times K2 and then divided by K1 to the
e. So by now this should look familiar to
这个方程中现在有两个变量。C会被攻击者知道
you. So now we have two variables in this
equation, of course. C is known to the
E和N也会被攻击者知道
attacker, E is known to the attacker, and
N is known to the attacker. The two
而这个方程的两个变量为K1和K2,我们将其
variables in this equation are K1 and
K2, and we've separated them into a
分到方程的两边，结果我们可以做一个这个方程的中间的满足攻击
different side of the equation, and as a
result we can do now a meet in the middle
现在来解决中间的满足攻击
attack on this equation. So let's do the
meet in the middle attack. What we would
建立一个包含左边式子所有可能值的表
do is we would build a table of all
possible values Of the left-hand side. So
K1的e次方分之C的所有可能值，有2的34次方个
all possible values of C over K1 to the E,
there are 2 to the 34 of them. And then,
而右边的所有可能值，即K2的e次方的所有可能值
for all possible values on the right-hand
side, [inaudible] for all possible values
第一步，我们要检查这个值是否在表中
of K2 to the e, we're gonna check whether
this value here lives in the table that we
如果我们发现一个碰撞
constructed in step one. And if it is then
we found a collision, and basically we
我们基本上就得到这个方程的解法了。当我们找到一个K2的e次方的元素
have a solution to this equation. So as
soon as we find an element of the form K2
在第一步建立的表中时，我们就解了这个方程
to the E that lives in the table that
we built in step one, we've solved this
并得到K1和K2。一旦我们找到了K1和K2
equation and we found K1 and K2. And
of course once we found K1 and K2,
我们就可以很简单地通过K1×K2将K还原出来
we can easily recover K simply by
multiplying them. So then we multiply K1
所以我们将K1×K2得到密钥K，所以我们已经破坏了加密系统
and K2 and we get, the secret key
K. Okay? So, we've broken, basically,
这花了多长时间？通过强行计算
this, this encryption system. And how long
did it take? Well, by brute force, we
我们大概打破了2的64次方的时间，只要尝试所有可能的密钥
could have broken it in time 2 to the 64,
simply by trying all possible keys. But
但是攻击者在步骤一就花了2的34次方时间
this attack, you notice, it took 2 to
the 34 time for step number one. Well, it
可能还不止这么长，因为我们不得不做取幂
took a little bit more than 2 to the 34,
'cause we had to do these exponentiations.
步骤二也需要2的34次方时间，可能因为取幂而多于这个时间
It took 2 to the 34 time for step two
against slightly more than two to the 34
所以这整个算法需要2的40次方时间
because of the exponentiations. So let's
say that the whole algorithm took time two
关键是，这大大减少了所需时间
to the 40. The point is that this is much,
much less time due to the 64. So here you
下面是一个例子，如果你直接使用RSA加密，换句话说
have an example. Where if you encrypt
using RSA directly, in other words you
你直接计算出K的e次方，模N而不通过ISO标准
directly compute, K to the E, mod N,
instead of going through the ISO standard,
你会受到攻击，并且并行起来比穷举搜索更快
for example, then you get an attack that
runs much faster than exhaustive search.
你受到的攻击运行需要2的40次方时间，而不是2的64次方
You get an attack that runs in time two to
the 40, rather than time two to the 64.
这是个好例子，说明密码可以破译如果直接用RSA陷门置换
Okay, so this is a cute example of how
things can break if you use the RSA
来加密信息。这里需要记住的是
trapdoor permutation directly to
encrypt a message. So the message to
千万不要直接使用RSA来加密。你得通过加密机制来加密
remember here, is never, ever, ever use
RSA directly to encrypt. You have to use to go
就像ISO标准一样
through an encryption mechanism. For
example, like the ISO standard. And in
事实上，下一节我们就会看到其他方式来使用RSA建立
fact, in the next segment we are going to
see other ways of using RSA to build
公用密钥加密
public key encryption.